# **Jermaine Blake**

## **Software Developer**

PHONE	EMAIL	ADDRESS	LINKEDIN
(416) 624-4220	info@jermaineblake.dev	Calgary, AB	linkedin.com/in/jermaineblake

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Full Stack Software Developer passionate and enthusiastic about learning and building purposeful applications backed by over 10 years of success across multiple business roles and a strong understanding of the full customer experience.

#### **PERSONAL PORTFOLIO & REPOSITORIES**

jermaineblake.dev

github.com/jermzblake

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

✓ Collaboration
 ✓ Problem-Solving
 ✓ Process Improvement

✓ Full-Stack Software Design & ✓ Applied NLP (semantic
 ✓ Adaptability
 Coding
 search, LLMs, embeddings)

✓ AI System Design
✓ Cross-Functional Engagement
✓ Emotional Intelligence

#### **TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES**

✓ RESTful APIs
✓ JavaScript
✓ Node.js

✓ SQL, NoSQL databases
✓ TypeScript
✓ Redis

✓ React
✓ Express & Koa
✓ Mongoose

✓ RAG Pipelines ✓ CSS & SaSS ✓ AWS

✓ MVC Frameworks
✓ Git/GitHub (version control)
✓ OOP

Jermaine is excellent at following through on tasks to make sure they are completed. Jermaine thinks through the different scenarios and possibilities to come up with a reasonable, well-thought-out solution.

Stuart Bustard, Area Manager, Enterprise Rent-a-Car

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate of Completion, General Assembly, Toronto Sept 2020 - Dec 2020 450+ hours, Software Engineering Immersive Program

Bachelor of Science, University of Guelph Sept 2006 – May 2011

Major, Biological Science, Graduated with Honours. Varsity football team member

# **Jermaine Blake**

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Black Professionals In Tech Network, Toronto, ON

Mar 2021 – Present

BPTN is bridging the network gap between Black talent and career opportunities across North America.

## **Senior Full Stack Software Developer**

- Built and launched, from inception, a Multi-Sided Networking Enterprise Platform (Obsidi).
- Acted as technical lead, collaborating with offshore developers, QA, and third-party DevOps to deliver scalable and secure backend services.
- Mentored junior developers and collaborated cross-functionally with data and product teams.
- Designed and implemented an Al-powered job matching feature leveraging Applied NLP (semantic search, LLMs, embeddings).
- Advocated for clean, reusable, and well-documented code while mentoring junior engineers and leading agile delivery cycles.

## Accomplishments and successes are highlighted to indicate the value offered and a consistent focus on excellence.

Full Stack Software Developer – BPTN		
Challenge	Our new offshore development team (along with our own QA) was having difficulty understanding and	
	utilizing API endpoints documented in Postman	
Solution	Add detailed descriptions of what endpoints were for, what their parameters were, what the response	
	should look like and any other pertinent details	
Result	Had less back and forth with offshore and QA teams to explain endpoints. This saved time and increased	
	productivity	

Full Stack Software Developer – BPTN		
Challenge	Al-generated candidate matches produced through RAG pipelines were slow and often returned too few	
	results.	
Solution	Streamlined the matching process by removing the generative AI layer and leveraging consolidated	
	candidate embeddings in a hybrid semantic + keyword search approach.	
Result	Improved search performance by 1000× faster retrieval and significantly increased the number of	
	qualified candidates surfaced per query.	

Full Stack Software Developer – BPTN		
Challenge	When sending emails from our Backend instance recipients were receiving duplicate emails.	
Solution	Set up a cron-job instance in our infrastructure to handle all automated jobs such as sending emails.	
Result	The application was able to handle multiple automated jobs without interfering with our normal backend processes and email recipients no longer received multiple emails	

Branch Manager – Enterprise Car Share		
Challenge	Undocumented damage costs were higher than expected.	
Solution	Implemented improved training and procedures for vehicle inspections, particularly with cargo vans which faced costly repairs. Implemented a video documentation procedure for staff usage for every vehicle inspection.	
Result	Undocumented damages were reduced by 60%.	

## **Jermaine Blake**

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (continued)

## **GENERAL ASSEMBLY TORONTO**, Toronto, ON

Sept 2020 - Dec 2020

General Assembly is a pioneer in education and career transformation, specializing in today's most in-demand skills.

### **Software Developer**

- Built full-stack web applications using Node.js, Express, MongoDB, React, PostgreSQL, Django technologies.
- Collaborated on a real-time, multiplayer, trivia application. Managed gitflow workflow for application by using branches for new features. Reviewed dozens of pull requests to ensure code quality and consistency.
- Implemented Object-Oriented Design process.
- Utilized Git and GitHub.
- Effectively coded design based on mock-ups and wire-frames utilizing CSS, Materialize, Bootstrap, and other front-end frameworks.

## ENTERPRISE CAR SHARE/RENT-A-CAR, Toronto, ON

Oct 2014 - July 2020

Enterprise offers carsharing services through two premier brands – Enterprise CarShare (U.S. and Canada) and Enterprise Car Club (U.K.).

## **Branch Manager**

- Developed Risk Management policies and processes to address loss, theft, and damage.
- Negotiated lease agreements in a highly competitive market with high-priced locations in Toronto.
- Developed partnerships and managed vendors and accounts.
- Conducted oversight for fleet management from maintenance and repair to recall projects, staff training and 3<sup>rd</sup> party vendors.
- Managed the branch Accounts Receivables and collections.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & AWARDS**

**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner** 

### **EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR (BPTN)**

#### **PASSIONS/INTERESTS**

Sports, Music, Technology, Gaming, Science, Education

Football Coach, Camp Olympia